writings
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- writings, 2.1.9.3
  - These Men Shall Never Die by Lowell Thomas, circa 1940s; 26 (Box 1612)
    - Verso: Joe Martinez, Right cartrage belt on shoulder, 22-verso
    - Lt. Jerry Kisters, 23
    - Verso: Lt. Jerry Kisters, 23-verso
    - Lt. Jerry Kisters, 24
    - Verso: Lt. Jerry Kisters, 24-verso
    - Lt. Jerry Kisters, 25
    - Verso: Lt. Jerry Kisters, 25-verso
    - Lt. Robert Spence Johnson, Mesa, Arizona, 26
    - Verso: Lt. Robert Spence Johnson, Mesa, Arizona, 26-verso
    - Lt. Robert Spence Johnson, Mesa, Arizona, 27
    - Verso: Lt. Robert Spence Johnson, Mesa, Arizona, 27-verso
    - Lt. Robert Spence Johnson, Mesa, Arizona, 28
    - Verso: Lt. Robert Spence Johnson, Mesa, Arizona, 28-verso
    - To my most beloved family, From "Donnie Boy"; Don S. Gentile, 29
    - Verso: To my most beloved family, From "Donnie Boy"; Don S. Gentile, 29-verso
    - To my most beloved family, From Don; Don S. Gentile, 30
    - Verso: To my most beloved family, From Don; Don S. Gentile, 30-verso
    - Don S. Gentile, 31
    - Verso: Don S. Gentile, 31-verso
    - Captain Charles Purcell Cecil, USN - Helena Series, 32
    - Verso: Captain Charles Purcell Cecil, USN - Helena Series, 32-verso
    - Duane W. Beeson, 33
    - Verso: Duane W. Beeson, 33-verso
    - Capt. Duane W. Beeson, 34
    - Verso: Capt. Duane W. Beeson, 34-verso
    - Captain Richard Ira Bong, 35
    - Verso: Captain Richard Ira Bong, 35-verso
    - Capt. Richard I. Bong (now mayor), 36
    - Verso: Capt. Richard I. Bong (now mayor), 36-verso
    - Lieutenant Commander Frederick B. Warder, USN, 37
    - Verso: Lieutenant Commander Frederick B. Warder, USN, 37-verso
    - Note[PDF]: [letter from Mary Warder to Lowell Thomas concening photograph of Commander Warder, 38
    - Pvt. Junior N. Van Noy, 39
    - Note: Pvt. Junior N. Van Noy, 40
  - These Men Shall Never Die by Lowell Thomas, circa 1940s; 27 (Box 1612)
    - [Portrait of uniformed man], 1
    - [Man hugging a baby], 2
    - [Three men standing together on road, the two at the sides are wearing graduation caps and gowns], 3
    - [Group of men in uniforms standing], 4
    - [Boy standing on steps], 5
    - [House], 6
    - Receiving DFC from Brig. Gen. W.C. Woodbury., 7
    - Verso: Receiving DFC from Brig. Gen. W.C. Woodbury., 7-verso
    - [Two men in flight gear, shaking hands in front of airplane propellar], 8
    - Carl + Capt. Mahnoin[?], 9
    - Verso: Carl + Capt. Mahnoin[?], 9-verso
  - These Men Shall Never Die by Lowell Thomas, circa 1940s; 28 (Box 1612)
    - December 1, 1942 - (h) Casablanca, French Morocco - Two French destroyers (foreground) and a light French cruiser beached north of Casablanca Harbor., 1
    - Verso: December 1, 1942 - (h) Casablanca, French Morocco - Two French destroyers (foreground) and a light French cruiser beached north of Casablanca Harbor., 1-verso
    - December 1, 1942 - (c) Casablanca, French Morocco - On the morning after the first attack this aerial reconnaissance photo was taken from a U.S. Navy plane. It shows five burning French ships in the various harbors of Casablanca. One can be seen burnign at the end of the large pier (top). Theother four are in the outer harbor, ranging from center to left, and the extreme lower left corner. At the end of the large pier, the French merchantship Porthos can be seen lying on its side., 2
    - Verso: December 1, 1942 - (c) Casablanca, French Morocco - On the morning after the first attack this aerial reconnaissance photo was taken from a U.S. Navy plane. It shows five burning French ships in the various harbors of Casablanca. One can be seen burnign at the end of the large pier (top). Theother four are in the outer harbor, ranging from center to left, and the extreme lower left corner. At the end of the large pier, the French merchantship Porthos can be seen lying on its side., 2-verso
    - December 1, 1942 - (d) Casablanca, French Morocco - A closeup view from the starboard side of the unfinished French battleship, Jean Bart, discloses damage near the bow and near the stern. Note also the shade and pier damaged as the result of bombing and shell fire from U. S. Fleet., 3
    - Verso: December 1, 1942 - (d) Casablanca, French Morocco - A closeup view from the starboard side of the unfinished French battleship, Jean Bart, discloses damage near the bow and near the stern. Note also the shade and pier damaged as the result of bombing and shell fire from U. S. Fleet., 3-verso
    - September, 1942 - HIT--Periscope photograph made by Pacific Fleet Submarine shows big Japanese freighter (not the case as in accompanying picture) broken in two after torpedoing in enemy homeland waters, and sinking., 4
    - Verso: September, 1942 - HIT--Periscope photograph made by Pacific Fleet Submarine shows big Japanese freighter (not the case as in accompanying picture) broken in two after torpedoing in enemy homeland waters, and sinking., 4-verso
    - An American Sub's Eye View of Sinking of a Japanese Destroyer: This remarkable photograph, the first combat action photograph taken through the periscope of an American submarine, shows and enemy destroyer of one of the latest and largest types after it had been struck by two torpedoes launched by the submarine from which the picture was taken. The destroyer sank in nine minutes. Note the Rising Sin insignia on top of the turret to the left, ehich serves as an identification mark for aircraft. Also note the two men in white scrambling over the conning tower to the right. The marks on the left and the center line are etchings on the periscope., 5
    - Verso: An American Sub's Eye View of Sinking of a Japanese Destroyer: This remarkable photograph, the first combat action photograph taken through the periscope of an American submarine, shows and enemy destroyer of one of the latest and largest types after it had been struck by two torpedoes launched by the submarine from which the picture was taken. The destroyer sank in nine minutes. Note the Rising Sin insignia on top of the turret to the left, ehich serves as an identification mark for aircraft. Also note the two men in white scrambling over the conning tower to the right. The marks on the left and the center line are etchings on the periscope., 5-verso
    - USS San Francisco (CA38), Heavy Cruiser, 6
    - Verso: USS San Francisco (CA38), Heavy Cruiser, 6-verso
    - The plane takes off in a cloud of spray as the mission "gets under way.", 7
    - Verso: The plane takes off in a cloud of spray as the mission "gets under way.", 7-verso
    - Last Pre War Photos from Wake Island - Wake Island as seen from the bow of a Navy Patrol Vessel, 8
    - Verso: Last Pre War Photos from Wake Island - Wake Island as seen from the bow of a Navy Patrol Vessel, 8-verso
    - [US Airplane], 9
    - November 6, 1942 - Remnant of a Rising Sun Bomber -- This wing section was the largest single piece remaining of a Japanese bomber after its bomb load was touched off by a U.S. Marine anti-aircraft shell at 20,000 feet. The plane disintegrated in the sky, bits raining down over a wide area., 10
    - Verso: November 6, 1942 - Remnant of a Rising Sun Bomber -- This wing section was the largest single piece remaining of a Japanese bomber after its bomb load was touched off by a U.S. Marine anti-aircraft shell at 20,000 feet. The plane disintegrated in the sky, bits raining down over a wide area., 10-verso
    - Boeing B-17A, 11
    - Verso: Boeing B-17A, 11-verso
    - December 2, 1942 - USS Oklahoma: Rescue crews are shown here working on the upturned hull of the 29,000-ton battleship USS Oklahoma, which capsised in Pearl Harbor after being blasted by Japanese warplanes. Holes were burned through the hull to permit the rescue of some of the men trapped below. Note one of the Oklahoma'S launches in the foreground. The battleship, USS Marylandis in the background., 12
    - Verso: December 2, 1942 - USS Oklahoma: Rescue crews are shown here working on the upturned hull of the 29,000-ton battleship USS Oklahoma, which capsised in Pearl Harbor after being blasted by Japanese warplanes. Holes were burned through the hull to permit the rescue of some of the men trapped below. Note one of the Oklahoma'S launches in the foreground. The battleship, USS Marylandis in the background., 12-verso
    - The USS Oklahoma, shown capsised following Japanese attack at Pearl Harbor, Hawaii Dec. 7, 1941., 13
    - Verso: The USS Oklahoma, shown capsised following Japanese attack at Pearl Harbor, Hawaii Dec. 7, 1941., 13-verso
    - December 2, 1942 - USS Maryland: Moored inboard of the USS Oklahoma which capsized, the 31,500 -ton Maryland was damaged slightly and was one of the first ships to rejoin the fleet after the Japanese attack.", 14
    - Verso: December 2, 1942 - USS Maryland: Moored inboard of the USS Oklahoma which capsized, the 31,500 -ton Maryland was damaged slightly and was one of the first ships to rejoin the fleet after the Japanese attack.", 14-verso
    - American soldiers are shown giving a drink to a dying Jap. Bataan Peninsula, P.I., 15
    - Note: American soldiers are shown giving a drink to a dying Jap. Bataan Peninsula, P.I., 16
    - Anti-tank troops moving an anti-tank gun into the firing position during recent maneuvers in P.I., 17
    - Note: Anti-tank troops moving an anti-tank gun into the firing position during recent maneuvers in P.I., 18
    - These soldiers are shown listening in to the "Voice of Freedom." Somewhere behind the lines this newscast was a constant headache to the Japs. Hatnan Peninsula, P.I., 19
    - Note: These soldiers are shown listening in to the "Voice of Freedom." Somewhere behind the lines this newscast was a constant headache to the Japs. Hatnan Peninsula, P.I., 20
  - On the Trail of the Condor by Lowell Thomas (suggestions for illustrations), circa 1931; 29 (Box 1612)
    - Note: Pan America, Suggestions for Illustrations, 1
    - Aconcagua - highest peak of the Americas, taken from Panagra Mailplane between Santiago, Chile, and Buenos Aries, 2
    - Verso: Aconcagua - highest peak of the Americas, taken from Panagra Mailplane between Santiago, Chile, and Buenos Aries, 2-verso
    - Mollando, 3
    - Verso: Mollando, 3-verso
    - Coastal Andes South of Huarmey, 4
    - Verso: Coastal Andes South of Huarmey, 4-verso
    - Country Club, Lima, 5
    - Verso: Country Club, Lima, 5-verso
    - Las Palmas Aerodrome, Lima. Showing part of The Pan-American Grace[?] Airways air fleet., 6
    - Verso: Las Palmas Aerodrome, Lima. Showing part of The Pan-American Grace[?] Airways air fleet., 6-verso
    - Panagna Liner over Camana, Peru, 7
    - Verso: Panagna Liner over Camana, Peru, 7-verso
    - [Man and mule in penguin rookery], 8
    - Lima 11,500, Alt., 9
    - Verso: Lima 11,500, Alt., 9-verso
    - Panagra Mail and Paneryer Planes in flight between Trujillo and Lima, Peru., 10
    - Verso: Panagra Mail and Paneryer Planes in flight between Trujillo and Lima, Peru., 10-verso
    - Pan-American Grace Airways "Panagra" - Ford Trimotor Panagra Mail Plane Flying Paupa[?] between Mandoza and Buenos Aires, 11
    - Verso: Pan-American Grace Airways "Panagra" - Ford Trimotor Panagra Mail Plane Flying Paupa[?] between Mandoza and Buenos Aires, 11-verso